[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo gettype(null);",
    "answers": ["null", "undefined", "object", "number"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (0.1 + 0.2 === 0.3) ? 'true' : 'false';",
    "answers": ["true", "false"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "Which of the following methods converts a PHP object to a JSON string?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["json_decode()", "json_encode()", "toString()", "json.toString()"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "What does the 'this' keyword refer to in a regular PHP function?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["The global object", "The object that called the function", "The function itself", "None of the above"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "How do you write a comment in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["<!-- This is a comment -->", "// This is a comment", "{/* This is a comment */}", "# This is a comment"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo [] + [];",
    "answers": ["[]", "null", "undefined", "\"\""],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a PHP data type?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["Boolean", "Null", "Undefined", "Float"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "Which of the following methods is used to add elements to an array in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["push()", "add()", "append()", "array_push()"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo gettype(NAN);",
    "answers": ["number", "string", "undefined", "object"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Which company developed PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["Microsoft", "Apple", "Netscape", "Zend Technologies"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "Which method can be used to create a new array from an existing array in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["slice()", "array_slice()", "split()", "array_map()"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Which of the following methods can be used to stop an interval timer in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["clearInterval()", "clearTimeout()", "stopInterval()", "stopTimeout()"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Which of the following is used to define a variable in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["var", "let", "const", "$"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (1 == '1') ? 'true' : 'false';",
    "answers": ["true", "false"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (1 === '1') ? 'true' : 'false';",
    "answers": ["true", "false"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "What is the correct syntax for referring to an external PHP script called 'script.php'?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["<script href='script.php'>", "<script name='script.php'>", "<script src='script.php'>", "<script file='script.php'>"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Which of the following is not a reserved word in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["interface", "throws", "program", "short"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "How do you declare a PHP variable?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["variable $carName;", "var $carName;", "let $carName;", "declare $carName;"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (0 == '');",
    "answers": ["true", "false"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (0 === '');",
    "answers": ["true", "false"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "What is the purpose of the 'debugger' statement in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["It stops the execution of PHP", "It triggers a breakpoint in the code", "It logs a message to the console", "It catches errors in the code"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 22,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo ([] === [] ? 'true' : 'false');",
    "answers": ["true", "false"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 23,
    "question": "What does 'NaN' stand for in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["Not a Null", "Number and Null", "Not a Number", "None of the above"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 24,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo ([1, 2, 3] + [4, 5, 6]);",
    "answers": ["[1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 6]", "[1, 2, 3][4, 5, 6]", "1,2,34,5,6", "undefined"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 25,
    "question": "What is the correct way to check if a variable 'x' is not equal to '5' in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["x <> 5", "x =! 5", "x != 5", "x !== 5"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 26,
    "question": "What is the output of the following code?",
    "code": "echo ('5' + 3);",
    "answers": ["8", "53", "Error", "undefined"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 27,
    "question": "Which function is used to parse a string to an integer in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["intval()", "floatval()", "Number()", "Integer()"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 28,
    "question": "Which of the following is a ternary operator in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["?", "!", "??", "&&"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 29,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (true + false);",
    "answers": ["truefalse", "1", "NaN", "undefined"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 30,
    "question": "Which method is used to round a number to its nearest integer in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["round()", "ceil()", "floor()", "trunc()"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 31,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo gettype(function(){});",
    "answers": ["object", "function", "undefined", "string"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 32,
    "question": "Which method is used to get the length of a string in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["length()", "str_length()", "count()", "strlen()"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 33,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo gettype(true);",
    "answers": ["boolean", "number", "object", "string"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 34,
    "question": "What is the correct way to include an external PHP file named 'header.php'?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["<php src='header.php'>", "<php name='header.php'>", "<php include='header.php'>", "<php require('header.php');"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 35,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (NULL === null) ? 'true' : 'false';",
    "answers": ["true", "false"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 36,
    "question": "What is the correct way to create a constant in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["const PI = 3.14;", "define(PI, 3.14);", "constant PI = 3.14;", "PI = 3.14;"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 37,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "$x = 5; echo ++$x;",
    "answers": ["5", "6", "Error", "undefined"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 38,
    "question": "Which method is used to get the current date and time in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["now()", "date()", "time()", "getdate()"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 39,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (5 * 2 ** 3);",
    "answers": ["80", "40", "10", "15"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 40,
    "question": "What is the correct way to comment multiple lines in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["<!-- This is a comment -->", "// This is a comment", "/* This is a comment */", "# This is a comment"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 41,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (5 % 2);",
    "answers": ["10", "5", "2.5", "1"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 42,
    "question": "What is the correct way to check if a variable 'x' is equal to '5' and of the same type in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["x == 5", "x = 5", "x === 5", "x !== 5"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 43,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "$x = 5; echo $x++;",
    "answers": ["4", "5", "6", "Error"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 44,
    "question": "Which method is used to remove whitespace from the beginning and end of a string in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["strip()", "trim()", "whitespace()", "removeWhitespace()"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 45,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "$x = 5; echo $x--;",
    "answers": ["4", "5", "6", "Error"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 46,
    "question": "Which method is used to get the index of an element in an array in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["index()", "findIndex()", "array_search()", "indexOf()"],
    "correctAnswer": 2
  },
  {
    "id": 47,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo 5 <=> 2;",
    "answers": ["-1", "1", "0", "true"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  },
  {
    "id": 48,
    "question": "What is the correct way to check if a variable 'x' is less than or equal to '5' in PHP?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["x <= 5", "x =< 5", "x =<= 5", "x =< 5"],
    "correctAnswer": 0
  },
  {
    "id": 49,
    "question": "What will the following code output?",
    "code": "echo (5 & 2);",
    "answers": ["10", "5", "2", "0"],
    "correctAnswer": 3
  },
  {
    "id": 50,
    "question": "What is the correct way to define a constant in PHP that is case-insensitive?",
    "code": "",
    "answers": ["const PI = 3.14;", "define(PI, 3.14, true);", "constant PI = 3.14;", "PI = 3.14;"],
    "correctAnswer": 1
  }
]
